clevergirlscollective.com 2016-05-31

# Privacy Policy — Clever Girls

## Privacy Policy of Clever Girls Collective

_Last updated November 16, 2015_

Welcome to Clever Girls Collective, Inc! We offer a network of bloggers and other influencers (collectively, "Influencers") that help our clients ("Clients") reach potential customers through social media. This Privacy Policy describes our privacy and data practices for our products and services.

This privacy policy describes the information we collect, how it is used how it may be shared, and what choices you have. This privacy policy is designed to cover all of our products and services, specifically including:

  * our website;
  * our application process to be Influencers; and
  * the Clever Girls Badge – a tool that is placed on blogs or websites of Influencers who are bloggers.

This privacy policy is deemed incorporated by reference into our [Terms of Service](http://www.clevergirlscollective.com/terms-of-service) and our [Clever Girls Collective Membership Agreement](http://member.clevergirlscollective.com/membership-agreement), [Instagram Elite Membership Agreement](http://instagram.clevergirlscollective.com/membership-agreement), [Team On 3 Membership Agreement](http://member.teamon3.co/membership-agreement).

**Our Website**

##### What We Collect from Visitors and How We Use It

Our company website ("Clever Girls Site” or “Site") is [www.clevergirlscollective.com](http://www.clevergirlscollective.com/). We collect personally identifiable information of Site visitors only from individuals who provide it to us knowingly and directly, such as when you apply to be an Influencer.

We log our visitor’s IP addresses to measure Site traffic, namely, how many unique visitors come to our Clever Girls Site. If we did not store the IP address, our Site audience count (number of visitors) would be inflated, because we would count each page load as one visit. By using the IP address, we can recognize duplicate visits from the same IP address, and derive the number of unique visits.

Additionally, we use third party website analytics services and tools to learn the URL of the site that our visitors came from and where they go next. This enables us to understand who is referring traffic to us and where traffic goes from our Site. We also may use analytics services to understand how visitors are using our Site.

##### How We Share That Information

We do not share information about our Clever Girls Site visitors with our Clients or third parties, except in the aggregate and except as provided for below with regard to Influencer Applicants.

##### Your Choices

Our Site does not allow you to opt out from our logging of your IP address. You can opt out of third party services that analyze your use of our Site as described in the section below titled “Managing your Choices – Including Third-Party Tracking or Advertising Activities.”

**Influencer Application Process**

##### Information Collected and Used About Applicants

Influencer applicants (" **Applicants** ") submit their applications through our Site. We collect the information that Applicants provide in the online application. This information may include personally and non-personally identifiable information.

The personally identifiable information may include your name and contact information, including email address and phone number. We use this information so that we can follow up with you.

Non-personally identifiable information may include demographic information, such as your age, gender, ethnicity, geographic location, interests, family, and education. We use this information to evaluate your likely match with Clients.

We assume that the readers of each Applicant’s blog or other social media are very similar in demographics and interests to those of the Applicant. Therefore, we evaluate whether potential Influencers will likely reach a Client’s target customers.

##### Sharing of Applicant Information

We may share aggregate or non-personally identifiable information about Applicants with our Clients or third parties. For example, we might share that 35 Applicants from Texas applied last year or that we have a network of 1,000 Influencers who have young children.

Once an Applicant becomes an Influencer, we may share some of their information with Clients. We do this in order to help match Influencers with particular Clients. For the matching process, we typically share non-personally identifiable data like interests and demographics. We may also share some personally-identifiable information, like Influencer’s name. We do not share personal contact information of Applicants, such as their email or phone number, with Clients, except with the Applicant’s express permission. We do not share personal contact information of Influencers with Clients, except with the Influencer’s express permission.

##### Your Choices

The data practices described above are needed for us to assess applications and manage the Influencer network. Accordingly, we do not offer opt-out mechanisms to Applicants in connection with the application process and network membership.

**Clever Girls Badge**

Influencers who are bloggers (" **Bloggers** ") are required to use or display a Clever Girls badge (" **Clever Girls Badge** ") on their own websites or blogs (" **Blogger Sites** "). We use the Clever Girls Badge as a tool to gather anonymous data about visitors to the Blogger Sites (" **Followers** ") so that we can understand how well our Bloggers are reaching our Clients’ target audiences.

##### How the Clever Girls Badge Collects Information

The Clever Girls Badge contains a pixel (a short string of software code) that collects the IP address of each visitor to each web page that it lives on, along with a record or “time stamp” of when the visit took place. This information reveals the size of the audience reached by the Blogger Site, which is a metric our Clients rely on to measure the effectiveness of Blogger campaigns. From the IP address, we can also infer the general geographic location of the computer the Follower used to access the Blogger Site.

The Clever Girls Badge pixel collects only non-personally identifiable information, including the Follower’s IP address, the Uniform Resource Locator ("URL") of the website visited before coming to the Blogger Site, and the type of browser used by the Follower.

Sometimes we allow a Client or a third party to "piggyback" on our pixel so that they can gather anonymous information about the Blogger’s audience using their own or third party browser cookies or web beacons. They may then use the information about Followers’ browsing behavior to learn what the Followers are interested in, and, in some cases, to subsequently show them ads that might be of interest to them, which is called targeted advertising.

We may use cookies and beacons for our own purposes, such as learning more about our Bloggers’ audiences, including their behavior after they leave Blogger Sites. The purpose of this would be to provide better services to our Clients and to measure the influence of the Bloggers.

##### How Follower Information is Used and Shared

We use Followers’ non-personally identifiable information to measure the audience of our Blogger Sites and to build an understanding of that audience. We assume that each Follower is like the Blogger in many ways. We gather demographic information about each of our Bloggers during the Influencer application process in an effort to learn, indirectly, about their audience. But we prefer to have actual data.

We buy demographic data and may combine it with the data we collect ourselves through the Clever Girls Badge to build profiles of Followers or learn more about them. This may help us better determine if Followers fit into our Client’s target geographic area or demographic or interest profile.

We provide Blogger audience data to our Clients, and may share with Clients Followers’ information in the aggregate, including non-personally identifiable information about Followers’ activities after they leave Blogger Sites to show the influence of the Blogger.

##### Your Choices

The Clever Girls Badge does not enable Followers to opt out from the pixel’s logging of their IP address and collection of non-personally identifiable information. However, a Follower may exercise certain choices over third party activities, including their use of cookies to show the Follower targeted advertising on other websites. These choices are described in the section below titled "Managing your Choices – Including Third-Party Tracking or Advertising Activities."

**Children’s Privacy**

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of thirteen (13) without parental consent, unless permitted by law. If we learn that a child under the age of thirteen (13) has provided us with personal information, we will delete it according to applicable law.

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**

We may update this privacy policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new policy online. If we make a material change in how we treat your personal information, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in advance of the planned change.

**Business Transitions**

Upon the sale or transfer of Clever Girls, Inc., and/or all or part of its assets, your data or information may be among the items sold or transferred. We will request that the purchaser treat your data according to the privacy notice in place at the time it was collected.

**Security Measures**

Clever Girls Inc. has put in place reasonable physical and technical measures to safeguard the information collected about you. However, please note that although we take reasonable steps to protect your information, no website or computer system or wireless connection is completely secure.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California law permits users who are California residents to request and obtain from us once a year, free of charge, a list of the third parties to whom we have disclosed their personal information (if any) for their direct marketing purposes in the prior calendar year, as well as the type of personal information disclosed to those parties. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please submit your request in an email to [membership@clevergirlscollective.com](mailto:membership@clevergirlscollective.com).

**Practices of Other Parties and Third-Party Sites**

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the privacy practices of our Clients, or the privacy practices of Blogger Sites. For that information, you should read their privacy policies when you visit their sites.

**Managing Your Choices – Including Third-Party Tracking or Advertising Activities**

To help provide you with choices about the information collected by third parties for their purposes, we provide you the following information about choices you have:

  * _Opting Out of Google Analytics_. We use Google Analytics to help us analyze how people are using our Site. To prevent Google Analytics from using your information for analytics, you may install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on by clicking [ https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

  * _Opting Out of ScoreCard Research_. We use ScoreCard Research to help us analyze how people are using our Site. To prevent ScoreCard Research from using your information for analytics, go to <https://www.scorecardresearch.com/preferences.aspx>.

  * _Opting out of MixPanel_. We use MixPanel to help us analyze how people are using our Site. To prevent MixPanel from using your information for analytics, go to <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>.

  * _Opting Out of Google Advertising_. We may allow Google to use a cookie to inform Google that you visited our Site, and Google may later serve ads to you on other websites. To opt out of Google interest-based advertising, click [https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated/).

  * _Opting Out of Targeted Advertising Generally_. The Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising program provides consumers with the ability to opt-out of having their online behavior recorded and used for advertising purposes by member companies. To opt-out of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes, click [http://www.aboutads.info/choices/](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) for instructions. Choices you make are both browser- and device-specific. This means that if you opt out when using Safari on your phone, you will not be opted out on Firefox or on your laptop.

  * _Do Not Track_. Some browsers have a ‘do not track’ feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These features are not yet uniform, so we are not currently set up to respond to those signals.

  * _Deleting cookies_. To manage or delete browser cookies, please see your browser's privacy settings.

  * _Flash Cookies_. We currently do not use flash cookies, but we may in the future. To control flash cookies, click <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html>. Flash cookies do not reside in your browser, so your browser settings will not affect them.

**International Users**

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that this site is hosted on our computer servers in the United States. Therefore, your information may be processed and stored in the United States. As a result, United States federal and state governments, courts, or law enforcement or regulatory agencies may be able to obtain disclosure of your information through laws applicable in the United States. Your use of our products or services or your submission of any personal information to us will constitute your consent to the transfer of your personal information outside of your home country, including the United States, which may provide for different data protection rules than in your country.

**Contact Us**

This Privacy Policy is brought to you be Clever Girls, Inc. We are located at:

2415 San Ramon Valley Blvd, Suite 4368, San Ramon, CA 94583

If you have further questions or comments, please feel to contact us at: [membership@clevergirlscollective.com](mailto:membership@clevergirlscollective.com).

## Privacy Statement for the Clever Girls Badge

_Last updated November 16, 2015_

Clever Girls Collective, Inc. (" **Clever Girls** ") offers a network of bloggers and other influencers (collectively, " **Influencers** ") that help their clients (" **Clients** ") reach potential customers through social media. This Privacy Statement describes the privacy and data practices regarding the Clever Girls Badge  \-- a tool that is placed on blogs or websites of Influencers who are bloggers (" **Bloggers** ").

**Who Uses the Clever Girls Badge**

As part of their membership into the Clever Girls Collective, **Bloggers** are required to use or display a Clever Girls badge ( " **Clever Girls Badge** ") on their own websites or blogs (" **Blogger Sites** "). Clever Girls uses the Clever Girls Badge as a tool to gather anonymous data about visitors to the Blogger Sites (" **Followers** ") to understand how well Bloggers are reaching the Clients’ target audiences.

**How the Clever Girls Badge Collects Information**

The Clever Girls Badge contains a pixel (a short string of software code) that collects the IP address of each visitor to each web page that it lives on, along with a record or “time stamp” of when the visit took place. This information reveals the size of the audience reached by the Blogger Site, which is a metric Clients rely on to measure the effectiveness of Blogger campaigns. From the IP address, the general geographic location of the computer the Follower used to access the Blogger Site can also be inferred

The Clever Girls Badge pixel collects only non-personally identifiable information, including the Follower’s IP address, the Uniform Resource Locator (“URL”) of the website visited before coming to the Blogger Site, and the type of browser used by the Follower.

Sometimes Clever Girls allows a Client or a third party to “piggyback” on its pixel so that they can gather anonymous information about the Blogger’s audience using their own or third party browser cookies or web beacons. They may then use the information about Followers’ browsing behavior to learn what the Followers are interested in, and, in some cases, to subsequently show them ads that might be of interest to them, which is called targeted advertising.

Clever Girls may use cookies and beacons for its own purposes, such as learning more about its Bloggers’ audiences, including their behavior after they leave Blogger Sites. The purpose of this would be to provide better services to their Clients and to measure the influence of the Bloggers.

**How Follower Information is Used and Shared**

Clever Girls uses Followers’ non-personally identifiable information to measure the audience of its Blogger Sites and to build an understanding of that audience. Clever Girls buys demographic data and may combine it with the data collected through the Badge to build profiles of Followers or learn more about them.  This may help Clever Girls better determine if Followers fit into a Client’s target geographic area or demographic or interest profile.

Clever Girls provides Blogger audience data to its Clients, and may share with Clients Followers’ information in the aggregate, including  non-personally identifiable information about Followers’ activities after they leave Blogger Sites to show the influence of the Blogger. 

**Your Choices**

The Clever Girls Badge does not enable Followers to opt out from the pixel’s logging of their IP address and collection of non-personally identifiable information.  However, a Follower may exercise certain choices over Clever Girls’ and third parties’ use of cookies to show the Follower targeted advertising on other websites.  These choices are described below: 

  * _Opting Out of Targeted Advertising._ The Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising program provides consumers with the ability to opt-out of having their online behavior recorded and used for advertising purposes by member companies. To opt-out of having your online behavior collected for advertising purposes, click <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/> for instructions.  Choices you make are both browser- and device-specific.  This means that if you opt out when using Safari on your phone, you will not be opted out on Firefox or on your laptop.  

  * _Do Not Track._ Some browsers have a ‘do not track’ feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These features are not yet uniform, so the Clever Girls Badge is not currently set up to respond to those signals.

  * _Deleting cookies._ To manage or delete browser cookies, please see your browser's privacy settings.

  * _Flash Cookies._  To control flash cookies, click <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html> Flash cookies do not reside in your browser, so your browser settings will not affect them.
